Guide to the Frank B. Swayze phonograph collection, 1962-1967 " MS2174
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Frank B. Swayze phonograph collection
circa 1962 - circa 1967
1962-1967
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Swayze, Frank B.
MS2174
0.25 Linear Feet
This collection contains twenty phonograph records of the Far East Network of the Armed Forces Radio and Television Service. The material dates from circa 1962 to circa 1967. The records are transcription discs of news programs, including Capitol Cloakroom, From the Capitol, Face the Nation, Issues and Answers, and Meet the Press.
Scope and Content note
This collection contains twenty phonograph records of the Far East Network of the Armed Forces Radio and Television Service. The material dates from circa 1962 to circa 1967. The records are transcription discs of news programs, including Capitol Cloakroom, From the Capitol, Washington Viewpoint, Face the Nation, Issues and Answers, Meet the Press, and Pin Point. Guests on these programs included U.S. senators, U.S. representatives, ambassadors, and non-elected U.S. officials. The phonograph records were saved from destruction by Capt. Frank Swayze, U.S.N. Ret., while he was stationed at Misawa Air Base in northern Japan (1971-1974). He gave them to GW in 2001.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Capt. Frank B. Swayze, U.S.N. Ret., 08/18/2001
Arrangement note
Organized according to date and disc ID number.
Biographic/Historical note
Capt. Frank Benjamin Swayze, U.S.N. Ret., collected the contents of this collection and donated them to GW. Swayze graduated from GW Law School in 1976. Swayze was a captain in the Judge Advocate General's Corp, U.S. Navy. He was stationed at Misawa Air Base in northern Japan from 1971-1974. Before retirement, Swayze worked at the Pentagon in the Office of the Judge Advocate General, International Law Division, and in the Office of the Secretary of Defense (International Security Affairs).
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Politics and government; Politics and culture -- United States -- 20th century; Radio broadcasting -- United States; Radio programs; United States. Armed Forces Radio and Television Service; Swayze, Frank B.
- From the Capitol - Sen. Karl E. Mundt and Capitol Cloakroom - Sen. Estes Keefauver - CC-25, 04/24/1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Washington Viewpoint - FAA administrator - RCF/RPL 22-4, 11/26/1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Face the Nation - Rep. Edwin Willis - Ku Klux Klan - RCF/RPL 41-5, 04/05/1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Capitol Cloakroom - Fed. Aid to the Arts and Sounds of Freedom - RCF/RPL 52-5, 06/21/1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Issues and Answers - Treas. Sec. Henry Fowler and From the Capitol - Sen. Jacob Javits - RCF/RPL 52-5, 06/21/1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Meet the Press - Amb. Adlai Stevenson and Capitol Cloakroom - Sen. John Tower and Sen. John Sparkman - RCF/RPL 1-6, 06/28/1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- From the Capitol - Sen. Edmund Muskie and Face the Nation - Gov. John Love - RPL 27-7, circa 07/02/1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Capitol Cloakroom - Guaranteed Annual Income and Samaritans with Wings - RPL 27-7, circa 07/02/1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Meet the Press - Rep. Gerald Ford and Rep. Melvin Laird and Issues and Answers - Sen. Mike Mansfield - RPL 29-7, 07/16/1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- From the Capitol - Mrs. Jean Dixon (Seer) and Capitol Cloakroom - Where does the U.S. stand in world affairs discussion - RPL 29-7, 01/1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Issues and Answers - Sen. Everett Dirkson and Face the Nation - Sen. Russell Long - RPL 30-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Meet the Press - McGeorge Bundy and Issues and Answers - Willy Brandt - RPL 31-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Meet the Press - South Vietnam Ambassador and Issues and Answers - Public TV - RPL 32-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Face the Nation - Sen. George Murphy and Capitol Cloakroom - Sen. Hardtke and Sen. Hruska - RPL 32-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Face the Nation - Clark Kerr and Issues and Answers - Treas. Sec. Henry Fowler - RPL 33-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Meet the Press - Sen. William Proxmire and Capitol Cloakroom - Poverty in the countryside- RPL 33-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Face the Nation - Rep. George Mahon and From the Capitol - Sen. George Aiken - RPL 34-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Capitol Cloakroom - Sen. William Proxmire and Sen. Peter Dominick and Pin Point - Former Asst. Ambassador to South Vietnam Fred Flot - RPL 34-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Face the Nation - Sen. Jacob Javits and Meet the Press - Bill Moyers - RPL 35-7, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)